[Xavier] Mutants. Since the
discovery of their existence...
They have been
regarded with fear...
Suspicion, ofi'en hatred
across the planet debate rages
are mutants the next link
in the evolutiona/y chain...
Or simpb/ a new species
of humanity...
F/gh ting for their share
of the world?
Either way,
it is an historical fact:
Sharing the world has never
been humanity's defining attribute.
[Whirring]
[ Woman ]
”we are not enemies, but friends.
“We must not be enemies.
“Though pass/on
may ha ve strained...
It must not break the bonds
of our affection.”
Lincoln said that in his first inaugural
address as our nation's 16th president.
It's one of my fiwor/tes.
So, if you'll please
ha ve your tickets ready...
We can begin the tour.
Jackie, could you clear
my schedule this evening?
I wanna have dinner with
my son. Yes, Mr. President.
[ Whooshing]
Excuse me, sir. Are you lost?
Perimeter breach
at visitor's checkpoint.
[ Whooshing] Multiple subjects.
Mr. President, security breach. Jackie,
leave. Let's get him out to the car.
[Whooshing]
Exit's not clear. We don't
know how many there are.
Post five. Secure. [ Whooshing]
[Grunts]
[ Bullets ricochet/ng ]
There's something in the corridor.
— to the shelter.
Negative! Not clear!
[ Growls] — [ Gunshots]
It's outside the oval office.
— lock this place down!
Don't shoot! — there!
[ Gunfire, mufiied] [ Thud]
[ Il/lan vells]
[Gunfire continues]
- [ Whooshing]
- [Gunfire]
- [ Man grunts]
[Gunfire dies out]
- — [Clatterabove]
- [ Whooshing]
[ Thud]
[Screams]
[Grunts] Mygod
[Hissing]
[Gunshot] — [ Gasps]
[Bird shrieks]
[ Wolf ho w//ng ]
Neanderthals. We once believed
that they were w/ped out...
By years of conflict with a much
more advanced branch ofhumanity...
Called cro—magnon man.
But recent research
into our own DNA...
Suggests that these two species
may have interbred...
Evolving into modern humans.
In other words, into
what? [Children] Us.
Us. Right.
Artie, not here.
[Recording of monstrous roar]
[Narrator on TV talking]
Come on. Pay attention.
[Narration continues]
[Hushed voices]
[Man] Makes me insane
when she does this.
- [ /ndistinct whispering]
- — what are you looking at, you s/ck...
- — [man ] Busted my lip.
[ Man #2] I have cancer.
— [ Man #3 ] To the shelter!
- [ Man #4 ] No!
- [Boy] Hi
- [ woman] They're gonna kill—
— [ G acophon y of voices]
What's wrong with this?
It doesn't work.
[ Whispering, /ndistinct]
Jean? You okay? [Stops] Yeah.
Yeah, I'm fine.
It's just, uh— just a headache.
It's not just a headache, is it?
Listen, I— I wasn't really
sure how to say this...
Scott. But ever since
Liberty island, you've been...
You've been different.
My telepathy's been off lately.
I can't seem to focus. I can hear
everything. It's not just your telepathy.
A month ago, you had to concentrate just to
levitate a book or a chair across the room.
Now, when you have a nightmare,
the entire bedroom shakes.
My dreams are getting worse.
Scott.
I keep feeling something terrible
is about to happen.
I would never let anything
happen to you.
Hey. Have you guys
seen Bobby and rogue?
Something's happening
in the food court.
My brother asked you a simple
question. Why are you being such a dick?
Yeah, why are you being
such a dick? [Metallic c linking ]
[ Boy] Because / can. [Snickers]
[Boy #2 ] C an I have a light?
Hmm.
Sorry. I can't help you out, pal.
— [ Rogue ] John, knock it off.
- [Laughing] — [ Bobby] Why
don't you stop showing off?
[John] For her? I can't help it if
your girlfriend's getting excited
- [Bobby] / don't think she's getting
excited — tiying to have a good time.
I think you're the only one
having a good time.
That's real cute, man.
What are you gonna do?
[Chuckles] Suddenly,
you're not so tough.
[Gasps]
- — [Commotion]
- [Laughing]
- — [ Bystanders murmuri'ng ]
- [Breathing heavily]
[ Bystanders silenced]
[Woman on cell phone]
Hello? Honey, can you hear me?
[Rogue] Bobby, what did you do?
I didn't do this. [Xa vier] No.
I did.
And the next time you
feel like showing ofi, ' don't.
[Man on TV] Breaking news. We're
coming to you live from Washington...
Where there's been an attack in
the oval ofifce of the white house.
Details are still coming in,
but we have been informed..
That the president and
vice-president were not harmed
sources say the attack
involved one or more mutants.
[Scott] / think
it's time to leave, professor.
Authorities have closed off—
[Xa vier] I think you're right.
- Yearrgh! Unh! [Breathing
heavily] — [commotion]
My opinion?
Magneto's behind this.
No. I don't think so, Scott.
While Eric is capable oforganizing
something like this from prison...
For him it would be irrational.
It would only hurt his goal
ofmutant prosperity.
You mean superiority.
You're right.
If Eric had his way— — of course, you
know how the government will respond.
They'll reintroduce
the registration act.
Or worse. The president could
declare a state ofemergency.
Place eve/y mutant
in the country under arrest.
Do you think the assassin
was working alone?
Well, we'll only know that if we
find him before the authorities do.
I've been trying to
track him using cerebro...
But his movements
are inexplicably erratic.
When I have
more exact coordinates...
Storm, Jean, I'll need you to
take thejet and try and pick him up.
It was close, wasn't it?
Closer than anyone's admitted.
What do you need, William?
Just your authorization...
For a special operation.
Uh, no, thank you,
Mr. President.
And somehow I thought you were
here to talk about school reform.
Funny you should say that,
Mr. President.
[ President ] Senator.
- Thank you for having me. — senator
Kelly, this is colonel William stryker.
How do you do? — his department has
been dealing with the mutant phenomenon...
Since before my time.
As I recall, you were a staunch
supporter of the registration act, senator.
It seems your ideas on the mutant
problem have changed recently.
For the best, I hope
so, what are you proposing,
Mr. Stryker?
Uh, may I, Mr. President?
[Knuckles cracking]
[Cracking continues]
We've managed to gather evidence
of a mutant training facility...
In the Salem region
of upstate New York.
Where did you
get this information?
Interrogation ofone of
the mutant terrorists...
From the Liberty island
incident.
Eric? Eric lehnsherr?
You have access to him?
[ S tiyker ] Magneto. Yes.
We developed the technology
that built his plastic prison.
This facility is a school.
— sure it is.
What the hell is that? A jet.
What kind ofjet?
— we don't know...
But it comes up
out of the basketball court.
[ S tiyker ] /f we 'd been allowed to do our
jobs, Mr. President, before this incident...
All right. Listen.
William, you enter,
you detain, you question...
But the last thing
we need to see...
Is the body of a mutant kid
on the 6:00 news.
Mr. Stryker. Senator Kelly.
This is yuriko,
my personal assistant.
Quite a handshake.
What can I do for you?
Uh, Eric lehnsherr's prison. I'd
like to arrange a visit if possible.
It isn't a petting zoo, senator.
In this conflict,
he is the enemy.
You'rejust a spectator. So why
don't you sit this one out, all right?
Conflict? Mr. Stryker, do you really
want to turn this into some kind of war?
I was piloting black—ops missions
in thejungles of north Vietnam...
While you were sucking on your
mama's tit at Woodstock, Kelly.
Don't lecture me about war.
This already is a war.
[Birds c hirping ]
Youtedeadfiyoutesodead.
[Chggks] Youtedead.
I— I don't wanna hurt you.
I'm not afraid.
Hey.
[Laughs]
[Motorcycle approaching]
Logan! Ifslogan.
You miss me, kid?
Not really. Mm. How you doing?
I'm okay. How are
you? Who's this?
Oh, this is Bobby. He's
my— I'm her boyfriend.
Call me iceman.
Right. Boyfriend?
So how do you guys...
Well, we're still
working on that.
Look who's come back.
Just in time.
For what? We need a baby—sitter.
Ba by—sitter? Nice to
see you again, Logan.
Hi, Logan. — hi, Jean.
Uh, /should go
and get the jet ready.
Yeah, well,
it was good to meet you.
Comeon ldkgo bye, Logan.
[Rogue] I'll see you later. —oby
storm and I
are heading to Boston.
We won't be gone long.
The professor wants us to track down
a mutant who attacked the president.
So it was a mutant?
You'll be here when we get back...
Unless you plan
on running offagain.
[ Inhales] Well, I can probably
think of a few reasons to stick around.
Find what you were
looking for, t ogan?
More or less.
I'll see you boys later.
Be safe, okay? — you too.
- Bye. — see ya.
Aren't you gonna
welcome me home?
Your bike needs gas.
Then fill her up.
[Gut/clfiskal] [Beeps]
[ Beeping]
[Exhales deeply]
Mr. Laurio.
How long can we keep this up?
How long is your sentence?
Forever. Not necessarily
forever, Mr. Lehnsherr.
Just until
I've got all that I need.
Mr. Stryker.
How kind of you to visit.
Have you come back to make sure the
tax-payers' dollars are keeping me comfortable?
[Rattling]
Ohh! [Groans]
[Moans]
[Groans]
[Exhales deeply]
Done. You can go.
Now...
Mr. Lehnsherr...
I'd like to have one final talk...
About the house
that Xavier built...
And the machine called cerebro.
Logan, my tolerance for your smoking
in the mansion notwithstanding...
Continue smoking that in here
and you'll spend the rest of your days...
Under the belief that
you're a six—year-old girl
you'd do that?
— I'd havejean braid your hair.
Welcome back.
[Gasps]
Ooh.
[ C erebro whirring ] You want
me to leave? [Clears throat]
No.just don't move.
These lights represent
every living person on the planet.
White lights are humans.
And these are the mutants.
[ Voices, /ndistinct]
Through cerebro,
I'm connected to them.
And they to me.
You see, Logan...
We're not as alone as you think.
[ V0ices continue]
I found the base at alkali lake.
There was nothing there.
The broken line represents the path of
the mutant who attacked the president.
I've been finding it difficult
to get a lock on him.
Well, can't you just
concentrate harder?
If I wanted to kill him, yes.
There.
[Xavier] T ooks like
he's finally stopped running
[speaking German]
/need you to read my mind again.
Loganm
I'm afraid the results
will be the same as before.
We had a deal. — the mind is not a box
that can be simply unlocked and opened.
It's a beehive with a million different
compartments. — spare me the lecture.
I have no doubt that your amnesia,
your adamantium skeleton, the claws...
Are all somehow connected
but, Logan...
Sometimes the mind needs to
discover things for itself.
I promise you we'll
talk again when I return.
Oh. If you will be kind enough
to watch over the children tonight...
Scott and I are going to
visit an old friend.
[Xa vier] / 'm sending coordinates of where
the mutant seems to have settled for now.
Soon as you find him,
bring him back to the mansion.
Let's hope he cooperates.
Yes. For his sake. Good luck.
[Birds c hirping ]
[Swish]
[Door hisses]
[Swish ]
[Stryker's voice]
Stryker, William.
[Door unlocks, hisses ]
What are you doing in here?
Esto y ti'rando la basura.
Garbage.
[Dog barking /n distance]
[ Wind whistling ]
[Creaking]
These are the coordinates.
[Birds c oomg ]
- [Man speaking German]
- [ Whooshing]
[ Whooshing]
[Man speaking German ]
[ Continues speaking German ]
[Whmthg] Hesatehpoflen
- [ whooshing] — must be why the
professor had trouble locking onto him.
- [Storm] We're not here to hurt you!
- [Birds fluttering]
We just wanna talk'
[speaking German]
Are you bored yet? — oh, yeah.
[Storm]
Sure you don't wanna come down?
[ Thundering ]
[ Wind whistling ]
[Screaming]
[Man breathing heavily]
- You have him?
- He's not going anywhere.
Are you?
Please don't kill me.
I didn't mean to harm anyone.
Now why would people
have gotten that impression?
[Storm ] What's your
name? Wagner. Kurt Wagner.
[ Kurt]
There was so much shooting..
Such fear...
And then there was only pain.
I could see it all happening...
But I couldn't stop myself.
/t was like a bad dream.
Perhaps he is testing me.
And before you were
in the white house...
What do you remember?
Nothing. I was here.
Jean.
I'd rather get him
back to the professor.
The professor?
Did you do these yourself?
Yes.
And what about this?
[Exhales deeply]
[ C linking ]
[Clinking continues]
[ T ogan ] I need you
to read my mind again.
[Xa vier] I'm afraid the results
will be the same as before.
[Man] He'll be indestructible.
[Man #2 ] His entire skeleton...
Adamant/um. [Xa vier] Sometimes the
mind needs to disco ver things for itself
Wolverine. [Eerie screech ]
[ Warbling voice]
No memo/y. He'll ha ve no mem0iy.
[ Grunting ] [Breathing heavily]
[Gasps]
[Breathing heavily]
[ Ne wscaster] A dozen tourists in
the white house during the attack...
Are still being
held for questioning
[man on TV] Best tasting food
a machine that's so darn easy...
President will
address the nation...
[Channels changing]
[ Woman ] For the white house
assassin, fol/o wing hundreds of...
Can't sleep?
How can you tell?
— 'cause you're awake.
Right. How about you?
[Channel changes]
Idontshep [channe/changes]
Hey.
Doesn't anybody
sleep around here?
Apparently not.
Gotanybeer? Thbisaschool
so that's a “no”?
Yeah, that's a “no.”
Got anything other
than chocolate milk?
There should be some soda
in that small cupboard.
Thanks nopmbhm.
I'll take him from here.
It's all right, Scott.
Nice shades. Thanks
[Electronic humming]
[ Door hisses ]
C har/es xa vier.
Ha ve you come to rescue me?
Sorry, Eric. Not today.
To what do I owe the pleasure?
The assassination attempt
on the president...
What do you know
about it? Nothing.
Only what I read in the papers.
You really shouldn't
have to ask, Charles.
What's happened to you?
I've had frequent visits
from William stryker.
You remember him, don't you?
William stryker.
His son, Jason, was once a
student ofyours, wasn't he?
Yes. Years ago.
Unfortunately,
I wasn't able to help him...
At least not in the way
that his father wanted.
And now you think
that taking in the Wolverine...
Will make up for your failure
with stryker's son.
[Insects c hirping ]
How long you been here?
Couple years.
And your parentsjust sent you off
to mutant school?
Actually, my parents
think this is a prep school.
Oh, I see.
I suppose lots of prep schools have
their own dorms, campuses— jets.
So you and rogue, huh? Yeah.
It's not what you think.
I'd like it to be, but it's just...
It's just that it's not easy...
When you wanna be
closer to someone...
But you can't.
You know, I've seen how
you look at Dr. Grey.
Excuse me? Nothing.
[Eric] You haven't told him
about his past, ha ve you?
I've put him on the path.
Logan's mind is still fragile.
Is it?
Or are you afraid of losing
one of your precious x—men...
Old friend?
Eric, what have you done?
I'm sorry, Charles.
I couldn't help it.
What have you told stryker?
[Sighs]
Everything.
The war has begun.
Scott! You should've killed
me when you had the chance!
[Yells]
[Groans]
[Knuckles cracking]
[Woman narrating on TV]
But now and then...
Every mother needs to get away.
Without her,
the babies are helpless.
Sensing danger,
the mother rat races home.
The babies can't
even see the killer.
And someone unin vited
is coming to dinner.
She arrives too late
for one baby.
The cent/pede was deadly.
[ TV continues, indistinct ]
- — [Grunts]
- [Thud]
[ Many footsteps ]
- What is it?
- Shh, shh.
[Dart gun firing]
[Gasps]
[Helicopters whirring]
You picked the wrong house, bub.
- [Tremendous shrieking]
- — [soldiers groaning]
[Shrieking continues] [Yelling]
[Shrieking continues]
[ Gunshots]
[Shrieking stops]
[Grunting]
[Grunts]
[Yells]
[Breathing heavily]
You all right?
Stay here.
[Muffled yelp]
[Groans]
[ Children screaming]
Come on! Run!
[Yemng]
Move, move, move!
[Helicopter whirring]
This way. Let's go. Come on!
[Breathing heavily]
[ C hi'ld moaning sofl'ly]
Go, go, go!
Run!
Run! John! Hey. Where's rogue?
I don't know. I gotta find her.
Come on! Here. Take her.
Hurry!
[Grunts]
Go on. Get in.
Let's go. Let's go.
Come on. Let's go! Come on!
Hey. Take him. He's stunned
I can help you. Help them.
[ C latter ]
- — [Soldier screams]
- [Machine gun fire]
Rogue! Bobbw
this way.
[Screams]
Come on. Everybody,
follow me up here.
[Helicopter whirring ]
Move! Move! Go! Go!
[Bobby] Come on.
[ Yelling]
[Soldiers groaning]
Let's go.
- [ Helicopter whirring]
- — come on. This way.
This is it.
Logan!
You wanna shoot me? Shoot me!
[ S tiyker ] Don't shoot him!
Not yet.
Wolverine?
Well, I must admit, this is
certainly the last place...
I'd expect to find you.
How long has it been?
Fifteen years?
You ha ven't changed one bit.
Me, on the other hand...
Nature.
Wait! Wait! You guys, we gotta do
something they're gonna kill him.
He can handle himself. Let's go.
— Bobby!
Please.
I didn't realize xa vier
was taking in animals...
Even animals as unique as you.
Who are you?
Don't you remember?
No! No!
Logan, come on. Let's go.
[Bobby] Logan go! Hlbefine
but we won't.
[ Device whirs, begins beeping]
Go. Keep going.
[ T ogan ] All right. Get
in. Get in! I'm driving.
Hey. Maybe next time.
This is cyclops's car.
Oh, yeah?
[Engine revving]
[Radio chatter]
What the hell
was that back there?
Stryker. His name is stryker.
[Rogue] Who is he?
I can't remember.
[Man on radio] Zone one clear.
[Man #2 on radio] Roger that.
Here. This is yours.
[Grunts] I don't like
uncomfortable silences.
- [— What are you d0ing?
- .Wipop]
[All groaning]
[ Whirring ]
I don't think
that's the cd player.
[Beeps] Vvhoa.
Sit back. — [device beeps]
Where we going? — storm andjean
are in Boston. We'll head that way.
My parents live in Boston.
— good.
[Radio chatter]
Sergeant?
Most of the mutants escaped through a series
oftunnels that weren't in our schematics.
We have several in custody.
[ S tiyker ] Howman y? Six, sir.
[Hi—pitched warbling]
[ Door hisses ]
[ Computer, female voice]
Welcome, professor.
Take what we need, gentlemen.
[Commotion]
[Man on TV] 1 ook, I just think
all this anti-mutant protesting..
Underscores the genuine growing
concern among most Americans.
I think mutant registration—
But why stop there?
Maybe it would be easier to
round up mutants by the truckload.
Or maybe you 'd like all—out
war, Mr. Shaw oh, please.
Turn that shit off, Lou.
[ Woman] Lot on your mind?
Mr. Laurio?
I'm grace.
You want another beer?
Of course you do.
[Door slams]
[Moaning]
[Laurio] You're really
aggressive. Yes, I am.
[Both moaning]
Oh, I— I've never hooked up
with a girl like you before.
[Chuckles] I know.
It's, uh, kinda dirty in here,
don't you think?
That's the idea. Velcro.
— [ Crackling]
Nice. Bottom's up.
I certainly hope so.
[Exhales deeply]
[Mug drops to floor]
[Belches]
[Clang]
Bottom's up.
William.
— please, Xavier, don't get up.
[ Electronic static]
I call it the neural inhibitor.
It keeps you outta here.
What have you done with Scott?
Don't worry. I'm just giving
him a little reeducation.
Of course, you know
all about that, don't you?
William, you wanted me
to cure your son.
But mutation is not a
disease. You're lying!
You were more frightened
ofhim than I was.
You kno w, lust one year after
Jason returned from yourschool...
My wife...
You see he resented us.
He blamed us for his condition.
So he would
toy with our minds...
Projecting visions
and scenarios into our brains.
Well, my wife, in the end...
She took a power drill
to her left temple...
In an attempt
to bore the images out.
My boy, the great illusionist.
[Crackling]
For someone who hates mutants...
You certainly keep
some strange company.
Oh, they serve their purpose...
As long as
they can be controlled
You arranged the attack
on the president.
You didn't even
have to read my mind.
You know, I've been working with
mutants as long as you have, Xavier...
But the most frustrating thing
I've learned...
Is that nobody really knows
how many even exist...
Or how to find them...
Except you.
Unfortunately, this little potion
won't work on you, will it?
You're much too powerful
for that.
Instead, we'll go
right to the source.
Allow me to introduce mutant 143.
The fluid secreted by his brain
acts as a mind—controlling agent.
[ Ma chin eiy hissin g ] But
that's only where it begins.
Jason.
Oh, my god, William.
This is your son.
What ha ve you done
to him? No, Charles!
My son is dead...
Just like the rest of you.
[Hissing continues]
[Gasps]
[Shouts] Mom? Dad? Ronny?
Is anybody home? [Clinking]
I'll try and find you
some clothes.
[Clinks] Don't burn anything.
Hey. I found some of
my mom's old clothes.
I think they're from
before I was born.
G roovy.
[Beeps] [Softstafic]
[Static continues]
Hello. [Static continues]
Come on, Jean. Where are you?
[Clock ticking]
These are my grandmother's.
Thanks.
You won't hurt me.
[Inhales deeply]
Wow.
[Breathing heavily]
[ Gasps] — I'm— I'm sorry.
[Exhales deeply] It's okay.
[Sniffing]
Mmm.
[Sofi' clatter]
[Purring]
[Door opens]
[A damantium claws retract]
[Cat meows] — [door shuts]
[Dad] Hey, Ronny. Next timeyou...
Who the hell are you?
Bobby. Uh...
Honey, aren't you
supposed to be at school?
[Dad] Bobby, who is this guy?
— uh, this is professor Logan.
[Cat meowmg]
There's something I need to tell you.
[Typing]
[Beeps] You're clear.
.U [ Classical piano ]
Have a nice sleep, lehnsherr?
There is something different
about you, Mr. Taurio.
Yeah. I was having a good day.
No. No, it's not that.
Sit down. — no.
[Baton clacks]
— sit your ass down.
What could it be? — [ Gasping]
What are you doing?
Ahh. There it is.
Too much iron in your blood.
[Gasping]
[Crackling]
[Grunts]
[Laughs]
Mr. Taurio, never trust
a beautiful woman...
Especially one
who's interested in you.
[ Plastic shattering ]
[Men groan]
[Clink]
[Clink] So, uh...
When did you first know
you were a...
[Clink]
[Lo/m] A mutant?
Would you cut that out?
[Dad] You have to
understand [clink]
We thought Bobby was
going to a school for the gifted.
Bobby is gifted. — we know
that. We just didn't realize he was...
We still love you, Bobby. It's
just this mutant problem is a little...
What mutant problem?
— complicated.
What exactly are you a
professor of, Mr. Logan?
Art.
[Rogue ] Well, you should
see what Bobby can do.
[Ice c rack/es ] [Mom] Bobby.
I can do a lot more than that.
[ Meows] — [chuckles]
[Breathing heavily]
Oh. Ronny!
This is all my fault.
[John] Actually...
They discovered that males are the ones
who carry the mutant gene and pass it on...
So it's his fault.
[ Tvnewscaster] The
assassination attempt...
[Dialing phone] [ Tine ringing]
[Woman]
911. Please state your emergency.
I need the police. There
are people in our house.
They won't let us leave. [TV]
Authorities refused to comment...
But it's believed that a manhunt
for several fugitives from the facility...
Is now underway.
[Beeping] Nobody's
responding. I can't get a signal.
Why don't you take a break?
I'll keep tiying
right.
[Speaking in German]
[Continues]
So, what are they?
They are angelic symbols...
Passed on to mankind
by the archangel Gabriel.
They're beautiful.
How many do you have?
One for every sin...
So quite a few.
You and miss grey
are schoolteachers?
Yes. At a school for people
like us... where we can be safe.
Safe from what?
Everyone else.
You know, outside of the circus,
most people were afraid of me.
But I didn't hate them.
I pitied them.
Do you know why?
Because most people
will never know anything...
Beyond what they see
with their own two eyes.
Well, I gave up on pity
a long time ago.
Someone so beautiful
should not be so angry.
Sometimes anger...
Can help you survive.
So can faith.
[Jean ] Storm, /found
an active com device.
Where?
[ Beeping]
Oh, it's for me.
Bobbym
have you tried
not being a mutant?
No one's left, Jean.
Soldiers came.
What about the children? Some of
them escaped I'm not sure about the rest
we haven't been able to reach
the professor or Scott either.
Where are you, Logan?
Boston, with Bobby Drake's family.
Okay. We're on our way.
— and storm? Make it fast.
Why? We have to go now.
No w! Logan, what's wrong?
Drop the knives
and put your hands in the air.
- [Logan] What's going on here?
- Ronny.
[Policeman] Isa/d drop
the knives. [Banging]
Open the door!
[Policeman] Break it.
[Screams] — turn around.
- — Up against the wall.
- Omw
this is just a misunderstanding.
Put the knives down.
I can't.
Look.
- Oh! — [screams]
All right, the rest of you,
on the ground now.
Look, kid isa/d on the ground
[ Police woman ] We
don't want to hun' you, kid.
You know all those dangerous
mutants you hear about on the news?
I'm the worst one.
[Siren blaring]
Look out!
[Gasps]
[ Wind whistling ]
[Jets whirring]
[Neck cracks]
Guten tag
who the hell is this?
Kurt Wagner.
But in the Munich circus, I was
known as “the incredible nightcrawler”...
Aw, save it. Storm? —
[Storm] We 're outta here.
[Engine re vving ] Whoa.
Jason, stop it!
[Gasps]
[Sniffiing]
- — [Crying softly]
- It's all right.
You can come out.
Have they gone?
Yes.
Where are all the other students?
— I don't know.
Well, then, we'll have to
find them, won't we?
We'll use cerebro.
Come on.
How far are we?
We're actually coming up
on the mansion now.
I've got two signals approaching.
Coming in fast.
[ Woman] Unidentified aircrafi', you
are ordered to descend to 20, 000 feet.
Return with our escort to hanscom air
force base. You have 70 seconds to complv.
- — Wow. Somebody's angry.
- I wonder why.
[ Woman] We are coming up alongside you
to escon' you to hanscom air force base.
I ower your altitude now
repeat, lo wer your altitude to 20,
000 feet this is your last warning.
They're falling back.
[ Beeping]
[Storm] They're marking us.
What?
— they're gonna fire. Hang on!
[Alarm continues beeping ]
[Storm] I gotta shake 'em.
Please don't do that again.
— I agree.
Don't we have
any weapons in this heap?
[Computer voice]
Warning, warning, warning.
Warning, warning, warning,
warning, warning.
warning, warning, warning
warning, warning, warning...
Everybody okay back there? — no.
[ Beeping]
Oh, my god. There's two of 'em.
There's one more.
Jean...
[Gasps] Oh, god!
[Screaming] — rogue!
- — No!
- [Alarm blaring ]
Jean? — it's not me.
[Panting]
When will these people
learn how to fly?
[Chuckles]
Thank you. Bitte scho'n.
Can you hear what they're
saying? — I could take a closer look.
His name is
colonel William stryker...
And he invaded your mansion
for one purpose:
He wanted cerebro.
Or enough of it
to build one of his own.
But that doesn't make any sense. S tiyker
would need the professor to operate it.
Which I think is the only reason
my old friend is still alive.
Oh, my god
now, what are you all so afraid of?
While c erebro is working,
c har/es' mind is connected..
To every living person
on the planet.
Ifhe were forced to concentrate
hard enough on a particular group...
Let's say, mutants, for example...
He could kill us all.
— waita minute.
How would s tiyker even know
where to find c erebro in the first place?
Because I told him.
I helped c har/es build it,
remember?
Mr. Stryker has powerful
methods of persuasion.
Even against a mutant
as strong as Charles.
So who's this stryker anjnnay?
He '5 a militaiy scien ti'St.
He spent his whole life trying
to solve the mutant problem.
If you want a more intimate
perspective, why don't you ask Wolverine?
You don't remember, do you?
William s tiyker, the only other man /
know who can manipulate adaman tium.
The metal on your bones.
It carries his signature.
But the professor—
— the professor trusted...
You were smart enough to
discover this on your own.
He gives you more credit
than I do.
Why do you need us? — mystique
has discovered plans of a base...
That's tiyker's been
operating out of for decades.
We know that's where
he's building the second cerebro...
But we don't know
where this base is...
And I believe one of you might.
The professor already tried. —
Once again, you think it's all about you.
Oh... hello.
I didn't mean to snoop.
Just try and relax.
[Gasps] I'm sorry.
Stryker's at alkali lake.
[ I ogan ] That's where the
professor sent me. There's nothing left.
There's nothing left on the surface,
Logan. The base is underground.
[Exhales]
Hey. Hey.
You okay?
Yeah. You sure?
How we doing? Not good.
It'll take four or five hours before
I can get it off the ground.
That's not what I meant.
I'm just worried about
Scott. I'm worried about you.
That was some display
of power up there.
Obviously, it wasn't enough.
Hey, hey. Come on. All right?
I love him.
Do you?
Girls flirt with
the dangerous guy, Logan...
They don't take him home.
They marry the good guy.
I could be the good guy.
Logan, the good guy
sticks around.
[Softly] Jean. Please. Please.
Don't make me dothe. Do what?
This.
Excuse me.
They say you can imitate
anybody... even their voice.
[Imitating nightcrawler]
Even their voice.
Then why not stay in
disguise all the time?
You know,
look like everyone else.
Because we shouldn't have to.
Look...
No one's ever left a scar
quite like you.
What do you want, an apology?
You know what I want.
But what do you want?
What do you really want?
I want you to get out.
Jesus.
Why don't we get uniforms?
Yeah, where's ours?
They're on order.
Should arrive in a few years.
[Chuckling]
We love what you've done
with your hair.
Hey, hey. Come on. Let's go.
So, they say you're the bad guy.
[Lgdnercwtkfiyg]
Isthatvvhat they say?
That's a dorky-looking
helmet what's it for?
This dorky-looking helmet is the
only thing that's gonna protect me...
From the real bad guys.
What's your name? —john.
What's your real name, John?
Pyro.
Quite a talent
you have there, pyro.
I can only manipulate the fire.
I can't create it.
You are a god among insects.
Never let anyone tell you different.
Sir, the machine has been
completed to all specifications.
Good.
Ow! [Electric c rack/e ]
If I may ask, sir, why are we
keeping the children here?
I'm a scientist, sergeant lyman.
When / build a machine, I
wanna make sure that it's working.
All right, this is a
topographic map of the dam.
This is the spillway.
You see these density
changes in the terrain?
They're tire tracks.
That's the entrance.
Mm-hmm. And this shows the depth
of the ice that's covering the ground.
Now, this is recent
water activity
if we go in there, stryker
could flood the spillway.
[Storm]
C an you telepon' inside?
No. I have to be able
to see where I'm going...
Otherwise / could
wind up inside a wall
I'll go. I have a hunch
he'll want me alive.
Wolverine, whoever goes into the dam needs
to be able to operate the spillway mechanism.
What do you intend to do?
Scratch it with your claws?
I'll take my chances.
But I won't.
Sir, there's someone
coming down the spillway.
I'm flooding it. Wait.
Stryker! [Echoing]
S tiyker!
Well, look who's come home.
[Guard] Move and you're dead
The one thing I know better
than anyone is my own work.
Seal the room. Shoot it.
Seal the room step away!
We have a metamorph loose.
Could be anybody.
Anybody? What...
Can you override
the spillway mechanism?
Everything's controlled from inside that
room. That's why the doors are so thick.
Oh, really? Get some
charges! Blow the doors open!
Take out these cameras!
I'm in.
She's good. You have no idea.
- [Man] Fire in the hole.
- [ Beeping ]
Move, move, move.
[Electrical c rack/ing ]
Sergeant, she's opened
the spillway doors.
More mutants have
entered the base. How many?
We've lost come. There is some
son' of electrical in terference...
Sergeant lyman, gather the rest of
your men and meet me outside cerebro.
You carry on. When I come back,
I want this door open all the way!
[Female computer v0ice ]
Welcome, professor.
Don't leave me alone, please?
— you can come inside.
[Loud creaking]
Have you found it?
A large portion ofenergy from the
dam has been diverted to this chamber.
[Storm ] C erebro.
[Magneto] There it is.
Can you shut it
down from here? No.
Come. There's little
time. Not without us.
Oh, my god. The children.
Kurt, will you come with me?
— yes.
[Storm] Where are they? [Mystique] They're
being held in a containment cell one level down.
Stryker. All right...
We'll get the children
and meet you at cerebro.
[Jean ] Okay. I'll tiy to find
Scott and the professor.
- — Will you be all right without us?
- Yeah. I'll be fine.
Where's Logan?
He's gone.
You, set up a perimeter.
[Man] Move, move.
Jason.
It's time.
Time to find our friends.
Is it time to find our friends?
All of them. — all of them?
All of the mutants.
— all the mutants?
Everywhere. — eveiywhere?
That's right. [ Girl]
Every one of them?
Oh, yes. [Girl] Good
it's time to bring it to an end.
Make me proud.
Just don't move.
Kill anyone who
approaches... even if it's me.
Go! I'll take care ofhim!
This is one lover's quarrel
we cannot get involved in, my dear.
[ Pantin g ] Scott!
Scott?
- [ Child] Help us!
- Anybody! — listen.
[ Children a t once]
Help! Get us out of here.
-Juhe? — storm.
Get us out of here!
Okay, we're comin g.
- [ Whooshing] — [ Gasping]
[Jean ] Scott!
Scott, don't do this!
[Cries out] Jean,
no, no, no. It's okay.
It's okay. It's me.
Scott. I'm so sorry.
I thought I'd lost you. Oh, god.
I'm so sorry. I could see you,
but I couldn't stop myself.
I tried. I'm sorry. I
love you so much.
I love you.
[Cries out] My leg.
Okay, easy. Easy.
Scott...
Something's wrong.
My god no!
[Girl] Ha ve you found the mutants
yet? Ha ve you found all of them?
[Xa vier] / 'm tiying.
There are so many of them.
[Girl] Then concentrate.
Concentrate.
[ Rumbling]
[Bubbling sound]
- [ Growling] — [claws slashing]
[Breathing heavily]
[Screaming]
The tricky thing about
adamantium is...
That if you ever
manage to process...
Its ra w, liquid form,
you gotta keep it that way.
Keep it hot.
Because once the metal cools,
it's indestructible.
But you already know that.
/used to think you were
one of a kind Wolverine.
I was wrong.
[A damantium claws extend]
Honsmt
[Neck cracks]
[Shouts] [Gasping]
[Groans, gasping]
[Growling]
[Panting, coughing]
That's it.
Whoa. Where do you
think you're going?
I'm sick of this kid's table shit.
I'm going in there.
[Rogue]
/ohn, they told us to stay here.
You always do as you're told?
[Gasping]
[Yemng]
[Grunting]
[Clank]
[Girl] Find all the mutants.
Find them.
Find all the mutants. Find
them all each one. All of them.
Good. [Ghflsvbke] Kmhhenz
[ whirring ]
[Metallic c lanking ]
[Screaming]
[Girl]
Concentrate. Concentrate harder.
Now, find them all.
Find all the mutants.
You, concentrate harder.
Ki'i/ them. Kill them all
ki'i/ them.
[Gasping] Cerebro.
We're too late. [Both screaming]
- — [Screaming]
- [Loud humming]
[Screaming]
Eric, hurry!
[Groaning]
[ Humming stops ]
That's strange.
[Breathing heavily]
[Whimpers]
How does it
look from there, Charles?
Still fighting the good fight?
From here, it doesn't look like
they're playing b y your rules.
Maybe it's time to play by theirs.
There's been a change ofplan.
[Whispering indistinct]
Good—bye, Charles.
There's been a change of plans.
Now find them. Find
them all— the humans.
Find all the humans. Every one.
[Groans]
[Screams]
[Whimpers]
How does it feel, bub?
Why did you come back? You
cut me open. You took my life!
You make it sound as if
I stole something from you.
As I recall, it was you who
volunteered for the procedure.
Who am I? You...
Are just a failed experiment.
[Cries out] [Grunts]
If you really knew
about your past...
What kind of person you were...
The work we did together...
People don't change, Wolverine.
You were an animal then.
You're an animal now.
I just gave you claws.
[Alarms blaring ]
[ Blaring continues]
[Rumbling]
[Alarm continues blaring ]
What the hell is that?
What is it?
The dam's ruptured. It's gonna
flood water into the spillway.
It's trying to relieve the pressure.
It's too late.
In a few minutes,
we'll all be underwater.
Come with me, and I'll tell you
everything you want to know.
You can't help your friends.
They're as good as dead, Wolverine.
You're a survivor,
always have been.
Oh, I thought I was just
an animal... with claws.
If we die, you die.
[Screams]
Aaah!
There are no exits that way, Wolverine!
[ Girl] Find all the humans.
Every one. Find them.
[ V0ice echoing] Find all
the humans. Find them all.
What is this? — cerebro.
Storm.
Jean. Are you
okay? Yeah. I'm fine.
What's happening?
Professor's still in there...
With another mutant.
He's trapped
in some kind ofillusion.
Oh, my god
ma gneto's reversed cerebro.
It's not targeting mutants anymore.
[Storm] Who is it
targeting? — everyone else.
[Grunting]
[I oud humming] [Yells]
Impossible. [Cries out]
[ V0ices c iyi'ng out]
[Screams continue ]
Everybody stand back. — Scott,
no. His mind is connected to cerebro.
Opening the door could kill him
and everyone his mind is linked to.
Wait. Kurt, I need
you to take me inside.
Storm, who is this guy? Who are
you? — my name is Kurt Wagner...
But in the Munich circus—
He's a teleporter.
I told you, if! Can't see
where I'm going...
I have faith in you.
Don't believe
anything you see in there.
Our father, who art in
heaven, hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come,
thy will be done on earth...
[Whooshing] As it is in heaven.
Hello.
What are you looking for?
Professor, can you hear me?
You've got to stop cerebro now.
— who are you talking to?
No. Don't move.
But she'sjust a little girl.
No, she's not.
I've got my eyes on you.
Mr. Stryker.
Funny, we keep
running into each other.
Mark my words,
it'll never happen again.
[Gasps]
Kurt, it's about
to get very cold in here.
I'm not going anjnnhere.
What are you doing?
[Shivered breathing]
[ Girl's voice]
Find all the humans. Kill them.
Every single one.
Find all the humans.
Focus. Focus.
[ V0ices gasping, ciyi'ng out]
- — Stop it!
- [Shivering]
[Vbkesconhnue
lndkhnct] [Shwenng]
Jason. He's going
to be so angry at me.
[ Screaming, gasping ]
[Panting]
[Whispering]
Logan. Logan, where are you?
[Alarm blaring ]
[Storm] We have to get
out through the spillway.
You don't want to go
that way. Trust me.
[ Rumbling]
Come on. There's
another way out of here.
The helicopter was right here!
[ Rumbling]
[Screaming]
[Breathing heavily]
I will take him. Okay.
[Vmhooshhyg] [Gasps]
It's okay, rogue. It's okay.
You can let go, honey.
Letgo. — go. I'll be fine.
Yousure? Yeah.
Who has the answers, Wolverine?
Those people?
That creature in your arms?
Huh?
[I ouder] Huh?
I'll take my chances with him.
One day, someone will finish
what I've started, Wolverine!
One day!
Scott, we've got to
get to Washington.
I fearthis has gone beyond alkali lake.
Bobby. I got 'im.
You okay?
I am now.
What's wrong?
— vertical thrusters are offline.
[Logan] So fix 'em. I'm tiying
has anyone seenjohn? — pyro?
Where the hell is he?
He's with Magneto.
[Storm] The y're functioning, but /
don't know how long they're gaing to last.
[Scott] I'm tiying to
override. It's not responding
[grunts] Come on! — [storm]
Oh, no, we've lost the power.
[Scott] There is power in the
fuel cells, we 're just not connecting
[storm] Okay. I've...
[Dialogue fades out]
[Gasps]
[Storm] Scott, the engine
control system is shot.
- — Which part?
- All of it.
- [Scott] Where's the override?
- [Storm] It's gonna take some time.
[Dialogue continues,
/ndistinct ]
[Scott] Storm, we need
some kind of external po wer.
Jean? — wait. Where isjean?
She's outside.
No, we're not leaving!
Lower the ramp!
[Scott] Storm, lower it!
I can't.
[Rumbling]
[Storm]
She's controlling the jet.
You, get her, now!
She's not letting me.
Damn it!
I know what I'm doing.
This is— — ...The only way.
Jean, listen to me.
Don't do this. Good-bye.
[Logan] Oh, no! No! — no! No! '
She's gone.
— don't you say that!
We gotta go back. She's gone.
No! No.
[Sobbing]
[Crying]
She's gone. She's gone. She's...
She's gone.
The lord is my Shepherd.
I shall not want.
He maketh me to lie down
in green pastures.
Yea, though I walk through the
valley of the shadow of the death...
I will fear no evil..
For thou art with me.
Today I've been given an opportunity
to shed light on recent occurrences...
From the attack that ended
in this office— good morning.
Good morning— to the unexplained
phenomenon that swept the earth...
Nearly annihilating our way of
life. Good morning, Mr. President.
- — Good morning. Do we like this word “annihilating”?
- [ Chattering]
Good morning.
[Cameras clicking] Good
morning, Mr. President.
Thank you.
Mr. President, we're live
in five, four, three, two...
My fellow Americans,
in this time ofadversity...
We are being offered a moment...
A moment to recognize a growing
threat within our own population...
And take a unique role
in the shape of human events.
[Static]
Did we just lose the feed?
Are we still live?
[ Thunder rumbling]
[ Thunder, louder]
Good morning, Mr. President.
Please, don't be alarmed
we 're not gaing to harm anyone.
Who are you people?
— we're mutants.
My name is c har/es xa vier.
Please, sit do wn.
I'd rather stand. — rogue.
These files were taken from the
private ofif'ces of William s tiyker.
How did you get this?
Well, let's just say I know a little girl
who can walk through walls.
I've ne ver seen this
informa tion. I know.
Then you also know
I don't respond well to threats.
Mr. President, this is not a threat.
This is an opportunity.
There are forces in this world
both mutant and human alike...
Who believe that a war is coming.
You will see from those files that
some have already tried to stait one...
And there have been casualties.
I osses on both sides.
Mr. President...
What you were about to tell the
world is true— this is a moment.
A moment to repeat
the mistakes of the past...
Or to work together
for a better future.
We're here to stay, Mr. President.
The next move is yours.
We'll be watching.
[ Thunderclap]
[Whispering] Mr. President.
You know...
Even whenjean was a student...
She was always hesitant
about her powers.
Always iookin g to others.
Feeling that in some way
she was left behind.
Do you think...
Could we have done
more to save her?
In the past, she may have let us.
There had to be another way.
Why did she Lea ve the plane?
Because she made a choice.
- [Knocking] - [Xavier]
- Yes, come on in.
Hey, hey.
Listen, she did make a choice.
It was you.
[Girl] Professor?
Is eveiything all right?
Yes, I think it will be.
Now, tell me, have any
of you read a book...
By an English novelist
named t.H. White...
Called the once and future king?
No? Well...
[ Continues, indistinct]
[Jean's v0ice ] Mutation.
/t is the key to our evolution.
/t is how we have evolved from
a single—celled organism...
Into the dominant species
on the planet.
This process is 5/0 w...
Normally taking thousands
and thousands of years.
But eveiy
few hundred mi'llennia...
Evolution leaps forward.